[ Watch on kissFlix.co ]
-Madam, look at these.
-Selling silk, selling silk!
-You won't find anything cheaper!
-The quality is remarkable.
Mistress painter.
Welcome, mistress painter.
How was your trip?
It is a sweltering day.
I am already quite wet.
Shall we begin then?
Hmm.
Can you capture all this in the painting?
I am capturing it in lines as soft
as the supple flesh of a boiled egg.
Take every pain…
to better capture him than me.
What kind of man is he?
He was a man
who was blessed below the waist.
As you know, mistress painter,
such a thing cannot be acquired
through training.
One is born with it,
as with any other thing.
He was greatly blessed indeed.
However, there were other blessings
apart from that.
Hmm?
Such as his tongue.
The tip was smooth as if wrapped in silk.
His hands were so strong.
The mere thought of it
makes my flesh tremble.
You must ensure to capture my expression.
Leave aside these trifling worries.
Carry on without pause.
It seems that he is beginning to move.
My hand is moving on its own,
as though possessed by a spirit.
Who on earth is this astounding person?
If he is truly bestowed
with such blessings,
I would like the honor
of meeting him myself.
Soon that may be difficult.
How so?
He did me a dishonor,
and I intend to do him the same.
He meddled with my one and only daughter.
What a wretched scoundrel.
Shall I intervene?
If you wish, I could personally ensure
he gets a stern lesson indeed.
You must be hurt.
Since that day,
I haven't sent you any word.
I cannot say that I was not hurt.
Just know that deceiving you
was not my intention.
But I found myself
growing fond of you, and…
I have thought on it a great deal.
It is a fact that you have told me lies,
which means I have been betrayed.
Thus, I cannot simply forgive you at once.
However, when I heard
my sister-in-law had passed away,
for some reason,
you immediately came to mind.
I realized that
I did not want to lose you.
But the fact remains,
I cannot commit an unfilial act.
After my brother passed away,
my mother has placed
great expectations on me.
Compared to my brother,
I am lacking.
But she believes I can excel,
so I cannot forsake my mother.
I apologize.
You're lying to me.
You just hate me, it's as simple as that.
Not at all.
That is not true.
I…
I do not hate you.
No, my lady, I…
Your face. What's happened to it?
Did you fall in the night?
Oh… I…
Don't tell me someone has struck you.
Uh, well…
Uh, I think that's how it's done,
or so I was taught.
My lady…
W-What were you taught?
Did… Did you not like it?
Oh, no!
I liked it.
I trust we shall meet again, young master?
Of course.
Your name is Eun-sil, is it not?
Yes, madam.
Eun-sil.
Young master.
I am here.
Over here.
Oh, young master.
Why are you here at this hour?
These are my lady's garments.
Even if we are to burn them,
I must wash them all first so my lady
can wear clean clothes as she passes on.
As for the other things,
Ganghwa told me
to throw them away at once.
Hmm. You seem busy.
We must still carry on.
Do head back inside.
Huh.
You keep your mouth shut. Understood?
Madam.
You have done well.
Would you like to come in
if you're truly so curious?
Uh… No, madam.
Good night, my lady.
Oh. A Catholic symbol.
Now, take a look at this.
Her Royal Highness
will be seated here in the middle.
And over here, the musicians and dancers
will fill the space in front of her.
My goodness.
What a wonderful, open view.
Her Royal Highness will be pleased, huh?
Yes. I am sure she will.
The banquet is the real test, of course.
The very thought of it makes my head ache.
I do think you exaggerate.
You have shown exceptional talent
during these preparations.
Hmm. Hmm.
You even made the trip
to see it in person.
We just have to convince His Majesty now.
Then I could be satisfied.
And yet…
-Huh?
-It seems rather unlikely
that such a busy man invited me
for no other reason.
Oh.
There's a royal decree as well
intended for you.
Hmm.
Uh…
By the way…
…there is something
I have always wondered.
This is not to say
I disregard your talents.
It's just…
Uh… I'll say what I mean.
It is common knowledge that
you are mainly an author of vulgar prose.
Yet, despite incurring
His Majesty's wrath,
how is it you are summoned
to the palace so often, hmm?
How did you manage
to secure a place by his side?
I have secured nothing for myself.
My place by His Majesty's side
is a punishment without end.
Hmm?
Oh.
Goodness.
You have come back.
Has all gone well with your affairs?
Sorry I'm late.
I meant to stay awake.
I apologize.
I'm sure you were very tired.
I could hear you snore.
What do you mean you heard me snore?
That is impossible.
There's no shame in it.
Even if thunder
were to roar from your nose…
…in my eyes, even Yang Guifei or Xi Shi
would pale in comparison
to one as lovely as you.
There's no need for such jokes.
I speak not in jest, but in earnest.
Sleep well, my lady.
I shall retire to the outer quarters.
Hardly a face for a lady.
Oh.
I'm sorry, my lady,
but can you write it in the proper script?
Why are you writing in the vernacular?
I am feigning ignorance,
lest knowing too well bring trouble.
Can knowing really bring so much trouble?
This petition is to be submitted
to His Majesty.
I have written it as I ought.
To His Majesty?
The lady of the Left State Councilor's
household has asked me for a favor,
so I have made a royal petition.
Most admirable.
You truly are the most remarkable woman
in all of Joseon.
That's enough flattery.
Could even a flower in full bloom
be fairer than this virtuous lady?
She was ever so serene
as she arrived in a white palanquin,
clad in mourning robes even as her
wedding clothes had scarcely been worn.
Seeing her mourn a husband
she had never known,
while devoting herself entirely
to the cultivation of chastity
and filial piety,
made my heart stir with pity many a time.
My lady.
Indeed, as a woman myself,
I believe that it is only right
to honor her
and make her virtue widely known.
Thus, I humbly present this petition,
though I am neither her kin
nor her in-law,
so she may stand as an example
to all women.
Did you compel her to do it?
Compel it?
What… Whatever do you mean?
That woman has asked the king to give
our daughter-in-law royal recognition!
Ah…
Can there be any doubt the poor girl
was a virtuous woman?
All of Hanyang knows it.
If I thought there was anything
I could do to help, even a little,
I would do it.
I did not seek to benefit myself.
I did it for our household.
After we lost Geum-ho,
what's left in this house
worthy of the name family?
My lady!
With Geum-ho,
this house lost more than a son.
It lost its pillar.
Its foundation.
If you will not take action,
my lord, I will.
What other way is there
of easing Geum-ho's grievance?
That grievance is your own.
Now that Geum-ho is dead, he has none.
We have not yet even found her body.
Restrain yourself.
Our Geum-ho…
he appears to me when I'm dreaming.
My son comes to me…
…and cries his poor heart out.
He does not speak a word.
He just sits there and cries.
At the very least,
we can build her a Memorial Gate.
That is the one thing I can do for him.
The only way to help my son.
My lady…
Father, it is In-Ho.
What's the matter?
Has something happened?
You're holding something. What is it?
I was in her room. I found this book.
INTRODUCTION TO
ESSENTIAL CATHOLIC TEACHINGS
Catholic teachings.
Huh?
Oh!
So you did not know
that my daughter-in-law
was a follower of the Catholics?
No, madam! I knew nothing about it!
Well, Ganghwa.
Yes, madam.
I don't care if she never walks again.
Beat this wench until she opens her mouth.
Yes, madam.
Madam! Madam, I swear it's the truth.
If I knew anything, I would surely tell.
Then…
I will change the question.
What did you take
from my daughter-in-law's room?
What?
You will only be punished further
if you lie.
Now tell me the truth.
That… I can't…
What's this? Are you hesitant to answer?
I will tell you!
I will tell you all!
What I took was…
the letters he sent…
The letters Lord Cho Won sent to my lady.
Cho Won?
You're referring to
Minister Yoo's brother-in-law?
He sent letters?
Ganghwa.
Yes, madam?
Get all the switches you can find
and bring them here.
I have a feeling
there's a lot more I need to hear
from this wretched girl's mouth.
Oh, dear.
Madam, I beg you to spare my life, please!
I did not want to do it. No!
I had no choice!
The lady of Minister Yoo's house
bid me to do it.
I swear, that is the truth!
Who?
Who put you up to it?
The lady of…
Minister Yoo's house.
Don't you think he looks like someone?
I'm not sure.
Though it may bear a resemblance to…
Lord Cho Won?
That settles it.
The plan worked.
That painter was well worth what I paid.
There was once a man
who went about scolding womanhoods
with his large hands.
It is said that there were many a woman
who wet their undergarments thanks to him.
Was the man's plying really so pleasing?
At that time, in Bukchon,
there lived a woman who went missing.
Perhaps she is somewhere
sitting across from this man
with her legs spread
and her breath coming quick and shallow.
Where on earth is the young woman now?
-The man must be depicted exactly.
-Yes, ma'am.
Pay particular heed to the man.
Yes, sir.
Madam, where are you?
I have news!
It has spread not only to Bukchon,
but also to Jungchon and Namchon.
I'm afraid to say it has prompted
the spread of strange rumors.
The timing is most unfortunate.
They say the councilor's
daughter-in-law is…
There once was a man…
"Come by when you get the chance."
-…who went about scolding womanhoods…
-"And scold my womanhood"…
-…with his large hands.
-…"with your large hands. I beg you."
I mean…
Heaven spare us,
it is positively scandalous.
Madam.
There you are.
Yes, madam.
I heard you called,
-so I dropped everything to--
-It seems we are both busy,
so let us come straight to the point.
Why have you been spreading these rumors?
Oh, um…
What rumors?
Do you have a grudge against my cousin?
Or perhaps…
the councilor's daughter-in-law?
If it is neither of those,
pray tell what I have done to wrong you
in any way?
Oh, you wrong me?
No, madam, you could never.
Then what is it?
For what reason have you done it?
Tell me, is there something you seek
from me perhaps?
Madam.
There is nothing more from you I desire.
My only wish from the beginning
was for my dear So-ok
to live as this house's
honorable concubine.
But if Lord Cho Won's visiting her room
be grounds for her being cast out,
how could her mother not be torn apart?
So, madam, all I would ask of you
is for your solemn promise
that So-ok will live her days as
a cherished member of this house forever.
I beg of you.
So you're threatening me now?
The likes of you…
Ganghwa! The palanquin is ready!
You have a merchant's spirit.
I grant your actions were bold.
Gather everything you have circulated.
It must not spread beyond the gates.
Yes. I will gather every single one.
I will stop them without fail.
Make no more sound. Leave quietly.
Yes, madam.
Hurry. Let us go.
Did you notice
an interesting paper
circulating in Bukchon?
The depicted in the drawing
and so described
certainly does look familiar.
I hope you don't think I'm troubled by it.
After all, did you not yourself,
some time ago,
make your cousin's faults known?
What use is there now in retracing
where and what faults he committed…
…or the shame he has brought to my house?
Ah.
I should say
how displeased I am that you knew
something yet persisted in deceiving me.
But I need not hear your explanations,
only this…
Make sure the things Eun-sil gave you
are handled with discretion.
Furthermore, I still need approval
for Hui-yeon's Memorial Gate.
If you wouldn't mind lending
a bit more effort,
that would be very nice.
Am I asking for too much?
Certainly not.
This little room
is a most interesting place.
It doesn't hurt?
Look there. That's your madam, isn't it?
Move closer to the side.
It's barely four steps from the house,
yet she insists on taking
the palanquin everywhere.
Gently!
Didn't I tell you to move gently?
Oh. Sorry. Did that hurt?
Why wouldn't it hurt?
It feels like my calves
are being torn apart.
All right.
Then I shall slither along like a snake.
You won't feel a thing, huh?
Slither.
Hurry up. I'll get scolded if I'm late.
As you wish.
Silk for sale! Come buy my silk!
-Slither, slither like this.
-No better silk in town.
Why has there been no word
from one who said he would come shortly?
There is something I must tell you,
so I would ask that you make haste.
My lord, with your leave, I shall enter.
Uh…
Oh.
Did you make all of this yourself?
I made them with Asan.
I have an idea. Here.
Like this. Hmm?
How's that?
Why don't we go like this?
I cannot see a thing.
Ah. Like this, then.
The things you are about to see,
you will never see again.
For today is no ordinary day.
We have many places to be.
Let us go out like this.
Like this.
Come in and peruse my wares!
Yeot, yeot! Get your yeot here!
Oh, my gracious lord,
come have a look at the yeot.
Oh, yes, indeed.
The sweetest yeot you'll find.
My word, you look so beautiful, my lady.
My lady.
It is very slippery here.
Come. Let's try like this.
Someday, we may find ourselves…
looking back upon tonight.
I fear that with time,
this memory shall grow faint.
I am terribly afraid.
So are you a coward then?
What has made you become sad
all of a sudden?
I am merely so happy…
that I'm almost…
starting to feel unsettled.
I would engrave you if I could, my lord.
I want to show you
what tonight has meant to me.
Will you accept it of me?
Engrave as deep as you can.
There's nothing I'd desire more.
Have you truly been summoned
to see His Majesty?
What? Is it so hard to believe?
Not at all. But…
it's just…
I feel there is much
I do not know about you.
I shall return before you go to bed.
All will be well.
Uh, we decided to work together.
I-I thought it would be safer
to follow her
than to spend the day on my own.
Now, when you say work,
surely you don't mean hard labor?
It will be all right.
All will be well, just as you said.
-But still, are-are you sure…
-Don't worry.
I will stay close by her side.
She won't tire herself.
Hurry and be on your way, young master.
Goodness, if you are to return
before she goes to bed,
you must hurry.
Oh. My lord!
Uh… Well…
I have engraved my heart into every word,
so please keep it deep, deep within yours.
Then, my dear cousin.
Can you provide the sounds
of that young widow opening herself to you
after decades with untarnished virtue
in a mature piece of heartfelt writing?
I shall return soon.
Good grief.
I was cutting it like this, you see.
But then I realized
I had not the strength for it,
and ended up falling on my bottom.
You have come just in time.
Your Majesty, it is your servant, Cho Won.
I have come from Hwaseong as you command.
I have well received your reply
to my confidential orders.
Indeed, construction appears
to be progressing swiftly.
It does, Your Majesty.
In particular, I noticed the artisans
have increased their efficiency.
I would surmise the reason is
their wages are being adjusted
according to their abilities.
They seem to take pride in that alone.
And it may also serve
to motivate the lower-ranking artisans
to strive even harder.
Yes.
I believe construction will be completed
several years earlier
than what you had previously planned.
Provided the high-ranking officials
cause no trouble.
Good.
I have other matters to attend to,
which is why I summoned you here in haste.
The councilor's daughter-in-law seems
to have gone back to her home for good.
Where she breathed her last,
it is not known,
for they could not find her body.
I wish to commend her filial piety,
but he insists that he must see the body.
How can I prevail
against such stubbornness?
I hear that her hometown lies
near the construction site of Hwaseong.
Could you join the search for her body?
I shall obey Your Majesty's command.
My goodness.
Go on in, miss.
Go have something to drink.
All right? Go on, go on.
All right. I will be back shortly.
Yes, yes.
Goodness, it's hot.
A little more…
A bountiful harvest this year!
Goodness,
these ripened splendidly, didn't they?
They have indeed.
Sister-in-law!
Sister-in-law.
Sister-in-law. It's In-ho.
So you live after all?
Brother-in-law.
How come?
How come you're here?
I came to see Master Cho Won.
But if you are here like this,
it must mean…
-I know how it seems.
-Hyah! Hyah!
Brother-in-law.
Brother-in-law!
Hyah.
-Ah.
-Lady So.
What brings you here at this hour?
Madam, have you heard yet?
About the councilor's daughter-in-law.
They are saying
that the girl's body hasn't been found.
My husband may not be of much use,
but he is still quick with the news.
Today, at His Majesty's court,
the king commanded her body be retrieved.
And he entrusted this task
to your own dear cousin,
Lord Cho Won, himself.
Why are you still waiting outside?
Young master.
You are quite late.